DIGITIZATION PROJECT/OPERATIONS MANAGER

Executive Summary

Results-focused management professional offering 10 years of progressive leadership experience. Transforms high-potential staff into outstanding leaders who demonstrate the creativity and savvy that is critical to financial and operational success.

Core Qualifications

- Operations management
- Staff development
- Policy/program development
- Cross-functional team management
- Computer-savvy
- Skilled negotiator
- Complex problem solving
- Sound judgment

Accomplishments

- Bccessfully grew business by [action].
- Project Management:
- Initiate

Professional Experience

Digitization Project/Operations Manager

April 2010 to March 2014 Atlas Technical Consultants, Inc. - Boise

- Hired as a subject matter expert to assist in the planning and implementation of procedures for the Cultural Imaginings project collaboration between George Washington University and Georgetown University funded by the Institute for Museum and Library Services to evaluate automatic book scanning methodology which produced the digitization of over 2000 books and over a million images.
- Maximized production efficiency through exceptional training, motivation, and oversight of staff members and work study students.
- Developed standard operating procedures and workflows to achieve the University's digitization initiatives.
- Managed the digital conversion of print, photographic, oversize, microfilm, audio and video materials.
- Set clear milestones for the team and provided regular and effective training to motivate and develop team members, as well as address
 areas for improvement.
- Supervised archival process, creation of metadata, and the ingestion of digital assets into a web base digital collection platform.
- Consulted with professors on campus to offer guidance on digitization for the advancement of their research needs.
- Researched and familiarized with copyright restrictions as it relates to digitization of cultural heritage materials.
- Managed the continued growth and development of digitization projects and implemented new projects as they arose, including identification and evaluation of potential digitization projects.
- Collaborated with Special Collections and Archives on the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Administrative files microfilm project in the digitization of 15,000 reels of microfilm from 1904 to the present.
- Worked with the universities within the Washington Research Library Consortium in developing standards and procedures for the digitization of over 700 bound books and over 168,000 images for the Yearbook digitization project.
- Consulted with National Institute of Health in the training of their staff and the post-processing of material for the Medical Heritage Library digitization project.
- Consultation with Gallaudet University in their digitization initiatives.
- Implemented workflow procedures, and trained staff on digitization hardware and digital editing software.
- Consultation with Catholic University of America on the digitization for the Strishock Print Collection.
- Collaborated closely with computer programmers in the Scholarly Technology Group in the Infrastructure project, and the development of tools to assist in digitization efficiency.

Digitization Project/Operations Manager

April 2010 to March 2014 3M Companies - San Bernardino

- Hired as a subject matter expert to assist in the planning and implementation of procedures for the Cultural Imaginings project collaboration between George Washington University and Georgetown University funded by the Institute for Museum and Library Services to evaluate automatic book scanning methodology.
- Maximized production efficiency through exceptional training, motivation, and oversight of staff members and work study students.
- Developed standard operating procedures and workflows to achieve the University's digitization initiatives.
- Managed the digital conversion of print, photographic, oversize, microfilm, audio and video materials.
- Set clear milestones for the team and provided regular and effective training to motivate and develop team members, as well as address
 areas for improvement.
- Supervised archival process, creation of metadata, and the ingestion of digital assets into a web base digital collection platform.
- Consulted with professors on campus to offer guidance on digitization for the advancement of their research needs.
- Researched and familiarized with copyright restrictions as it relates to digitization of cultural heritage materials.
- Managed the continued growth and development of digitization projects and implemented new projects as they arose, including identification and evaluation of potential digitization projects.
- Collaborated with Special Collections and Archives on the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Administrative files microfilm project in the digitization of 15,000 reels of microfilm from 1904 to the present.
- Worked with the universities within the Washington Research Library Consortium in developing standards and procedures for the digitization of over 700 bound books and over 168,000 images for the Yearbook digitization project.

- Consulted with National Institute of Health in the training of their staff and the post-processing of material for the Medical Heritage Library digitization project.
- Consultation with Gallaudet University in their digitization initiatives.
- Implemented workflow procedures, and trained staff on digitization hardware and digital editing software.
- Consultation with Catholic University of America on the digitization for the Strishock Print Collection.
- Collaborated closely with computer programmers in the Scholarly Technology Group in the Infrastructure project, and the development of tools to assist in digitization efficiency.

Project/Operations Manager

January 2005 to January 2009 KIRTAS TECHNOLOGIES - City, STATE

Project Manager

- Project management for a \$500 thousand digitization project for the collaboration between the American Psychological Association and the
 University of Akron to digitize books and gray literature from the Archives of the History of American Psychology (AHAP) historical
 collection for inclusion in APA databases.
- Ensured quality and consistency of digital records and metadata.
- Increased profits by developing, initiating, and managing the business process.
- Determined means and methods for assessing production quality.
- Managed project execution to ensure adherence to budget, schedule, and scope of work.
- · Worked with key stakeholders to develop policies, procedures, workflows and a manageable approach to support a dynamic program
- Managed the process of quality control and quality assurance of digital records and metadata.
- Contributed to the Microsoft Live Book Search project.
- Worked on digitization projects for Yale and Cornell University.

Education

1995 KINESIOLOGY AND PHSIOLOGY Portsmouth New Hampshire

Completion of 129 Credits BUSINESS MANAGEMENT University of Maine - City, State

Southern New Hampshire University Completion of 33 Credits

2000 2009 PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL TrainAce Academy - City, State American Library Association Digital Libraries Document Capture Community Integrated Document Management Professionals The Document Imaging Group National Information Standards Organization Project discovery and planning Multi-team projects Budgeting Internal and external communications Inventory Control Skills

Administrative, approach, audio, book, Budgeting, budget, BUSINESS MANAGEMENT, business process, oral, hardware, Consultation, conversion, databases, Document Management, editing, functional, Imaging, Inventory Control, managing, materials, 2000, Operations management, develop policies, problem solving skills, program development, Project management, Psychology, quality, quality assurance, quality control, Research, scanning, Staff development, team management, video, workflow, written communication skills